# Alejandro Sabogal Software and Web Developer

954-261-1961 asabogal.dev@gmail.com

alejandro-sabogal.com

github.com/asabogal

Proficient with React, Next.js, JavaScript, Node/Express, Ruby on Rails. Passionate about bridging creativity and technology. Efficient with smart and responsive Front-End design, and precise at building Back-End architectures. Experienced in Audio Technology, Hospitality, Finance, and Business Administration. Bilingual in English and Spanish.

#### **SKILLS**

React, Next.js, Hooks, Context API, Redux, Styled Components, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Node, Express, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Postgres, MongoDB, ActiveRecord, RESTful API, MVC Architectures, Google Cloud, Google Firebase, Heroku.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

React Developer, Freelance - The Umbrella NYC - Remote/New York, NY | September 2020 - current

- \* Developed two Front-End projects with the use of React: antib0dy.club and OffGrid (in progress).
- \* Transformed designer frames and slides into working micro-sites with Styled Components and CSS3.
- \* Built several custom React Hooks for improved user navigation and site interaction.
- \* Architected user onboarding with custom authentication and use of OAuth for Google and Facebook logins.

## Next.js and Node/Express Developer, Freelance - kontiki-gp.com - New York, NY | July 2020 - current

- \* Designed the UI/UX with React Styled Components and responsive CSS3 grid and flex.
- \* Utilized Next.js to architect both the front and back end interfaces.
- \* Engineered a Back-End API for a table reservation system and admin center with Node/Express and MongoDB.

#### Web Developer, Freelance - galleryhotelny.com - New York, NY | July 2019

- \* Rebuilt the website from scratch from a templated version to a custom made design with React and Styled Components.
- \* Maintained a guest and user database by integrating Google's Firebase.

# SELECTED PERSONAL PROJECTS - Additional Projects and Full Portfolio at: alejandro-sabogal.com

Creator, Project - cryptofolio-tracker.com - REACT AND RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - 2019

Interactive Cryptocurrency Portfolio Web App. Fetches real-time and historical crypto data - GitHub Repo

- \* Utilized React Context API for state management. React Router for protected and auth routes.
- \* Designed the UI/UX with React Styled Components and responsive CSS3 grid/flex.
- \* Implemented user authentication with Session Cookies and Bcrypt encryption.
- \* Architected the Rails API to persist user and fetched crypto data with PostgreSQL.

## Creator, Project - recordbox-reviews.com - RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - 2018

User authenticated vinyl record collection manager web-app - GitHub Repo

- \* Architected this Rails only application with MVC design and RESTful patterns.
- \* Provided user authentication with the Facebook SDK and OmniAuth with Bcrypt encryption.
- \* Utilized Google Cloud Platform and Postgres for data persistence and storage.
- \* Chosen as the student highlight project of the Flatiron School's Rails curriculum.

## **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

Business Consultant - CRPMNY Property Management - New York, NY 2016 - 2019

Audio Engineer - The Kitchen Studios - Miami, FL | 2011 - 2016

Co-Founder/Owner - PL0T Bookings and Events - Miami, FL | 2008 - 2015

#### **EDUCATION**

Full-Stack Software and Web Development - Flatiron School - New York, NY | 2019

Audio Technology and Engineering - SAE Institute of Technology - Miami, FL

Finance and Business Administration - Florida International University - Miami, FL